Guide to the William J. Baumol Papers, 1928-2013 and undated RL.00092
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
- Writings, 1946-2012 and undated
  - Articles, Book Chapters, and Other Papers, 1946-2012 and undated; 1
    - International Failures of the Invisible Hand: Theory and Implications for International Market Dominance, 1981 (Box 48)
    - Intertemporal Failures of the Invisible Hand: Theory and Implications for International Market Dominance, 1980-1981 (Box 1)
    - Intro to Reinecius and Themes that Emerged, 1983 (Box 48)
      Includes drafts of writings on the economics of arts and performing arts co-authored with Hilda Baumol
    - Introduction to Early Mathematical Economists Volume, 1991 (Box 48)
    - Introductory Paragraph for Wengenroth paper, undated (Box 48)
    - Introductory Remarks to 'Unsettled Questions in the Political Economy of the Arts', 1994 (Box 48)
    - Investment and Discount Rates Under Capital Rationing - A Programming Approach, 1965 (Box 48)
    - Investment, population growth and stationarity of Ricardian type, 1986 (Box 6)
    - Involuntary Unemployment in Say and Ricardo, 1983-1986; 9 text files; less than 1 MB. (Digital-materials RL00092-SET-0001, Disk RL00092-FL5-0108)
    - Is Incremental Productivity Convergence Illusory, 1987 (Box 48)
    - Is International Productivity Convergence Illusory? Comment on De Long's comment, 1988 (Box 6)
    - Is Japan Beating Us at Everything?, 1990 (Box 1)
    - Is Japan Beating Us in Everything, 1990 (Box 48)
    - Is there a European Economics?, 1994-1995 (Box 37)
      Includes related correspondence
    - Is There a U.S. Productivity Crisis, 1988 (Box 6)
    - Is There a U.S. Productivity Crisis, 1989 (Box 48)
      Reprint, drafts, and correspondence
    - It Takes Two to Tango, or Sind "Separable Externalities" Uberhaupt Moglich, 1976 (Box 48)
    - J.B. Say on Unemployment and Public Works, 1997 (Box 37)
    - J.B. Say on Unemployment and Public Works, 1997 (Box 48)
    - Jacob Viner at Princeton, 1972 (Box 29)
    - Jacob Viner in the Princeton faculty, 1995 (Box 37)
    - Jean Baptiste Say and the Traite, 1986 (Box 6)
    - JEP Interview with Baumol, 2001 (Box 36)
    - John R. Hicks' Contributions to Economics, 1972 (Box 29)
    - Journal of Political Economy, undated (Box 13)
      Includes note about galley proofs
    - Keynes on Malthus on 'Say's Law', 1990 (Box 6)
    - Keynes on Malthus on Say's Law, 1990; 2 text files; less than 1 MB. (Digital-materials RL00092-SET-0001, Disk RL00092-FL5-0028)
    - Keynesian Economics Encyclopedia Contribution, 1994 (Box 23)
      Includes correspondence about writing a biography of Alan Blinder for the Keynesian encyclopedia
    - Lecture in Appreciation of Luigi Pasinetti's Book, 2009 (Box 48)
      Proof
    - Leningrad Paper, 1975 (Box 48)
      Draft paper titled "On the Theory and Practice of Discount-Factor Calculation in Cost-Benefit Analysis", includes Russian translation
    - Leontief's Great Leap Forward: Beyond Quesnay, Marx and von Bortkiewicz, 2000 (Box 48)
    - Les Decisions Multivariees dans la Theorie de L'Oligopole, 1971 (Box 48)
      Reprint in French
    - Les dynamiques de desequilibre et le mecanisme de croissance de la productivite, 1995 (Box 48)
    - Letter for the Editor, 2003 (Box 48)
      Copy of letter to the editor in the Wall Street Journal
    - Letter from the Editors, AERE Newsletter, 1981 (Box 48)
      Copy of newsletter published by the Association of Environmental and Resource Economists
    - Linear and Integer Programming, 1963 (Box 48)
      Reprint of symposium proceedings
    - Linear Ricardo Model, 1995 (Box 48)
      Reprint and working paper
    - Lionel Robbins, 1984 (Box 26)
    - Lionel Robbins, 1985 (Box 48)
    - Lionel Robbins Memorial Talk, 1984 (Box 3)
    - Long Run Growth in US Productivity: Is There a Slowdown, 1980; 2 text files; less than 1 MB. (Digital-materials RL00092-SET-0001, Disk RL00092-FL5-0062)
    - Long-Run Trends in Environmental Quality, 1993 (Box 1)
      Copy and draft
    - Long-run trends in environmental quality, 1995 (Box 24)
    - Long-Term Productivity Growth: the role of feedback and entrepreneurship, 1992; 2 folders (Box 25)
    - Machine and Creative Judgement, 1962 (Box 48)
    - Machlup Memorial Service, 1985 (Box 3)
    - Macroeconomics of Unbalanced Growth, 1967 (Box 48)
    - Magnification, 1956 (Box 48)
    - Maledizione! Or, the perilous prospects of Beethoven's Patrons, 2001 (Box 18)
    - Maledizione! Or, the perilous prospects of Beethoven's Patrons, 2000 (Box 25)
    - Maledizione! Or, the perilous prospects of Beethoven's Patrons, 1997 (Box 38)
    - Maledizione! Or, the perilous prospects of Beethoven's Patrons, 2002 (Box 48)
    - Manual of Pricing and Cost Determination for Organizations Engaged in Dissemination of Knowledge, 1977 (Box 48)
    - Marginalism and the Demand for Cash in Light of Operations Research Experience, 1958 (Box 48)
    - Market Incentives, 1999 (Box 29)
    - Marketing Costs and Mathematical Programming, 1957 (Box 48)
    - Marx and the Iron Law of Wages, 1982 (Box 48)
    - Marx Papers, 1975 (Box 48)
      Reprints and drafts of multiple papers on Marx by Baumol
    - Mass Media and the Cost Disease, 1984 (Box 18)
      Copy, draft, and research materials for paper co-authored with Hilda Baumol
    - Mass Media and the Cost Disease, 1984 (Box 48)
    - Matching Private Incentives to Public Goals, Undated (Box 29)
    - Mathematical Analysis of Portfolio Selection, 1966 (Box 48)
    - Mathematical Models and Thinking in Marketing, 1960 (Box 48)
    - Mathematics for Economists, 1947 (Box 48)
    - MBA Program Study, 1992 (Box 5)
      Includes data for study on MBA programs with Malkiel
    - Microeconomia Come Cultura, 1986 (Box 48)
      Interview with Baumol in Italian
    - Microeconomics and the Engine of Free-Market Growth, 2003 (Box 48)
    - Microtheory of Entrepreneurship: More Exists than is Recognized, 2005 (Box 25)
    - Minimum and Maximum Pricing Principles for Residual Regulation, 1979 (Box 48)
    - Models for Systematic Evaluation of Alternative Retirement Policies, 1982 (Box 48)
    - Models of Economic Competition, 1965 (Box 48)
    - Models of Oligopolistic Competition, 1970 (Box 48)
    - Modified Fiscal Incentives in Environmental Policy, 1980 (Box 48)
    - Monetary and Value Theory: Comments, 1960 (Box 48)
    - Monopolistic Competition and Welfare Economics, 1964 (Box 48)
    - More on Proper Interconnection Pricing, 1998 (Box 48)
    - More on Proper Interconnection Pricing, 1998 (Box 49)
    - More on the Multiplier Effects of a Balanced Budget, 1955 (Box 49)
    - More on the Multiplier Effects of a Balanced Budget, 1955 (Box 84)
      Notes and related correspondence with Alvin Hansen and others
    - Multivariate Growth Process: Contagion as Possible Source of Convergence, 1991-1992; 2 folders (Box 5)
    - Museums and Virtuous Price Discrimination, 2004 (Box 49)
    - Musings on an Analysis of Vertical Integration, 1979 (Box 4)
    - Musings on an Analysis of Vertical Integration, 1979 (Box 17)
    - Musings on vertical integration, 1996 (Box 38)
    - National Resources, 2002 (Box 49)
    - Natural Monopoly and Contestable Market Analysis, undated (Box 17)
    - Natural Resources Depletion, 1992 (Box 4)
    - Neumann-Morgenstern Utility Index - An Ordinalist View, 1951 (Box 49)
    - New Economy and Ubiquitous Competitive Price Discrimination, 2003 (Box 49)
    - New Economy and Ubiquitous Competitive Price Discrimination, and other papers, 1996-2002 (Box 26)
    - New Palgrave Dictionary of Money and Finance Entries, 1991 (Box 49)
      Correspondence
    - New Wealth for Old Nations: Scotland's Economic Prospects, 2003-2004; 10 folders (Box 34)
      Drafts, research materials, and related correspondence
    - Newspaper editorials, 1979-1983 (Box 49)
      Drafts of various editorials
    - Notes on Some Dynamic Models, 1948 (Box 49)
    - Notes on the Present Status of the Wage and Interest Controversy, undated (Box 49)
    - Notes on the Theory of Government Procurement, 1947 (Box 49)
    - Oligopoly Theory and Retail Food Pricing, 1964 (Box 49)
    - On a Program for Long Run Productivity Growth in the US, 1992 (Box 49)
    - On Austrian Analysis of Entrepreneurship and My Own, 2003 (Box 49)
    - On Contracting with Publishers, undated (Box 14)
    - On Contracting with Publishers: Author's Information Updated, 1983 (Box 49)
    - On Contracting with Publishers: Or What Every Author Should Know, 1967 (Box 49)
    - On Disequilibrium Dynamics and the Mechanism of Productivity Growth: Implications for the role of 'Bounded Rationality', 1994 (Box 1)
    - On Distribution, Lump-Sum Transfers, and Innovation Spillover, 1999 (Box 24)
      Draft paper for Brookings Institute tribute to Arthus Okun
    - On Dividend Policy and Market Imperfections, 1963 (Box 49)
    - On Entrepreneurship, Growth and Rent seeking, 2003 (Box 37)
    - On environmental policy for a conservative era, 1999 (Box 25)
    - On environmental policy for a conservative era, 1999 (Box 36)
    - On Finances of the Performing Arts During Stagflation, 1980 (Box 18)
    - On Finances of the Performing Arts During Stagflation, 1980 (Box 49)
    - On Formal Dynamics: From Lundberg to Chaos Analysis, 1987 (Box 1)
    - On Income Distribution and Growth, 2007 (Box 26)
    - On Industry Differences in Absolute Productivity, and other papers, 1984; 2000 (Box 26)
    - On Inflation and the Arts, 1982 (Box 49)
    - On Interindustry Differences in Absolute Productivity, 1983-1984; 2 folders (Box 4)
    - On Interindustry Differences in Absolute Productivity, 1983 (Box 49)
    - On Location of Industries Among Trading Countries: Scale Economics as Possible Offset to Comparative Disadvantage, 1995 (Box 5)
    - On Mechanisms Underlying the Growing Share of Service Employment in the Industrialized Economies, 2003-2007 (Box 26)
    - On Method in U.S. Economics a Century Earlier, 1985 (Box 49)
    - On Method in US Economics: A Century Earlier, 1985 (Box 3)
    - On My Attitudes: Sociopolitical And Methodological, 1984 (Box 3)
    - On My Attitudes: Sociopolitical and Methodological, 1984-1985; 2 folders (Box 49)
      Drafts and copy of published paper
    - On my Attitudes: Sociopolitical And Methodological, 1991 (Box 6)
    - On My Computer Paintings, 2007 (Box 49)
    - On My Rejected Articles, 1993 (Box 1)
    - On My Rejected Articles, 1992 (Box 49)
    - On My Sculptures of Carved Wood, 1980 (Box 4)
    - On My Sculptures of Carved Wood, 1982 (Box 29)
    - On My Sculptures of Carved Wood, 1982 (Box 49)
    - On Productivity Growth in the Long Run, 1984; 2 folders (Box 5)
    - On Professor Neisser On Magnification, 1959 (Box 49)
    - On Public-Interest Principles for Economic Regulation, 1992 (Box 23)
    - On Recycling as a Moot Environmental Issue, 1977 (Box 49)
    - On Regulation of Utilities Under Deregulation, 1981 (Box 49)
    - On Some Microeconomic Issues In Inflation Theory, 1979 (Box 49)
    - On the Appropriate Discount Rate For Evaluation of Public Projects, 1967 (Box 49)
    - On the behavioral theory of the firm, 1971 (Box 49)
    - On the career of a microeconomist, 1983 (Box 49)
    - On the Cost Disease and its true policy Implications for the arts, Undated (Box 18)
      Draft of paper co-authored with Hilda Baumol
    - On the Economics of Musical Composition in Mozart's Vienna, 1991-1994; 2 folders (Box 17)
      Includes copies, drafts, working papers, and research materials for article co-authored with Hilda Baumol
    - On the Economics of Musical Composition in Mozart's Vienna, 1994 (Box 49)
    - On the economics of performing arts in the USSR and the USA: a preliminary comparison of the data, 1990 (Box 1)
      Drafts and research materials for paper co-authored with Hilda Baumol and Alexandre Rubinstein
    - On the Economics of the Performing Arts in the USSR and the USA, 1989-1990; 10 text files; less than 1 MB. (Digital-materials RL00092-SET-0001, Disk RL00092-FL5-0037)
    - On the Economics of Pre Merger Divestiture, undated (Box 17)
    - On the Economics of Pre-Merger Divestiture, 1985 (Box 23)
    - On the Economics of the Performing Arts in the USSR and the USA, 1990; 2 folders (Box 49)
    - On the Finances of the Performing Arts, 1980 (Box 49)
    - On the Financial Problems of the City, 1967 (Box 49)
    - On the Folklore of Marxism, 1979 (Box 29)
    - On the Folklore of Marxism, 1979 (Box 49)
    - On the Fringe: The State of Retirement Contributions and Other Nonpecuniary Family Benefits, 1962 (Box 49)
    - On the Geometry of 2nd Best, 1965 (Box 49)
    - On the Optimality of Public-Goods Pricing with Exclusion Devices, 1977 (Box 49)
    - On the Performing Arts: The Anatomy of their Economic Problems, 1965 (Box 49)
    - On the Perils of Privatization, 1993 (Box 49)
      Reprint and draft
    - On the pleasures and gains of collaboration, 1995 (Box 37)
    - On the Possibility of Continuing Expansion of Finite Resources, 1985 (Box 3)
    - On the Proper Cost Tests for Natural Monopoly in a Multiproduct Industry, 1977 (Box 49)
    - On the Reality of Economic Illusion, 1984 (Box 3)
    - On the Reality of Economic Illusion, 1984 (Box 17)
    - On the Role of Marketing Theory, 1957 (Box 49)
    - On the Social Benefits of the Arts and Humanities Principles and Quantitative Valuation, 1984 (Box 17)
    - On the Social Rate of Discount, 2000 (Box 26)
    - On the Social Rate of Discount, 1968 (Box 49)
    - On the Stochastic Unemployment Distribution Model and the Long-Run Phillips Curve, 1978 (Box 49)
    - On the Theory of Expansion of the Firm, 1962 (Box 49)
    - On the Theory of Oligopoly, 1958 (Box 49)
    - On the Theory of Perfectly Contestable Markets, 1982 (Box 49)
    - On the Theory of Productivity and Unbalanced Growth, 1979 (Box 5)
    - On the Work of Lionel Robbins, Robbins Volume, 1986; 2 folders (Box 3)
    - On Tomorrow's Economics, 1991 (Box 2)
    - One true cure for the social costs of organized crime, 1993 (Box 37)
    - Optimal Cash Balance Proposition: Maurice Allais's Priority, 1989 (Box 49)
    - Optimal Departures from Marginal Cost Pricing, 1970 (Box 50)
    - Optimal Departures from Marginal Cost Pricing, Cross Elasticity and Competition, undated (Box 17)
    - Optimal Depreciation Policy, 1971 (Box 29)
    - Optimal lags in a Schumpeterian innovation process, 1977 (Box 14)
    - Option Value Analysis and Telephone Access Chargers, 1999 (Box 25)
    - Option Value Analysis and Telephone Access Charges, 1999 (Box 50)
    - Origin of Monopoly Profits, undated (Box 50)
    - Output Distribution Frontier, 1978 (Box 50)
    - Outsourcing: Perils and Promises, 2006 (Box 50)
    - Overview of the Results on Consumption, Health, and Social Behavior, 1974 (Box 50)
    - Palgrave Dictionary, 1985-1987 (Box 3)
    - Palgrave Entrepreneurship Entry, 2006 (Box 50)
      Includes draft of entry for the updated New Palgrave Dictionary of Economics
    - Palgrave entries, 1984 (Box 50)
      Includes drafts of entries for the New Palgrave Dictionary of Economics
    - Paper on Leontief, 2009 (Box 50)
      Includes correspondence with editor
    - Papers in Process, 1991-1999 (Box 24)
    - Paradox Lost, or how R and D can impede productivity growth, 1982 (Box 4)
    - Paradox of the Services: Exploding Costs, Persistent Demand, 1999-2000; 3 folders (Box 38)
    - Pareto Optimal Sizes of Innovation Spillovers, 1997; 2 folders (Box 50)
      Draft and working paper
    - Parity Pricing and Its Critics, 1996-1997; 2 folders (Box 50)
      Reprint, proofs, drafts
    - Peak Load Pricing and Fairness, Arrow Volume, Ed. Feiwel, 1985 (Box 12)
    - Peak Pricing, Congestion, and Fairness, 1986 (Box 14)
    - Peak Pricing, Congestion, and Fairness, 1981; 2 folders (Box 50)
    - Perfect Markets and Easy Virtue, 1991-1992; 3 folders (Box 1)
    - Performing Arts Face Dim Economic Future, 1965 (Box 50)
    - Performing Arts: The Permanent Crisis, 1967 (Box 50)
    - Perils of Privatization, 1993 (Box 1)
      Proofs and related correspondence
    - Phillips and stabilization policy as a threat to stability, 1995 (Box 36)
    - Pig in the Python, 2002 (Box 26)
    - Pitfalls in contracyclical policies, 1961 (Box 50)
    - Pitfalls in Contracyclical Policy, 1981 (Box 17)
      Corrections and related correspondence
    - Planning and Dual Values of Linearized Nonlinear Programs, 1979 (Box 50)
    - Planning Research and Writing out the Results, Undated (Box 14)
    - Planning Research and Writing Out the Results, undated (Box 50)
    - Policy for Toxic Waste, 1985 (Box 3)
    - Political Economy, Growth, and Convergence, 1992 (Box 25)
    - Popular Misconceptions about Chinese Dining Customs, undated (Box 50)
    - Possible JEL Entrepreneurship Survey Article, 2006-2007 (Box 50)
      Draft and correspondence
    - Precursors in Mathematical Economics, 1968; 2 folders (Box 84)
      Drafts, notes, and research materials
    - Predation Criteria in the Swedish Postal Zone Price Case - A Reply, 1999-2000 (Box 50)
      Proof and draft
    - Predation Criteria in the Swedish Postal Zone Price Case -A Reply, 2000 (Box 26)
    - Preface: Lord Robbins, 1983 (Box 14)
    - Price Behavior, Stability, and Growth, 1958 (Box 50)
    - Price Caps; A Rational Means to Protect Telecommunications Consumers and Competition, 1988 (Box 3)
    - Price Controls for Medical Services and the Medical Needs of the Nation's Elderly, 1988 (Box 2)
    - Price Controls for Medical Services and the Medical Needs of the Nation's Elderly, 1988; 2 folders (Box 50)
      Report and draft
    - Price-Iso Return Locus and Rational Rate Regulation, 1979 (Box 50)
    - Pricing of Inputs Sold to Competitors, 1994 (Box 50)
    - Principle of the Operation of Public Enterprise, 1980 (Box 50)
    - Principles Relevant to Predatory Pricing, 2003 (Box 50)
    - Private Affluence - Public Squalor, 1992 (Box 50)
    - Private litigation for the purpose of constraining competition, 1995 (Box 37)
    - Privatization, Competitive Entry and Rational Rules for Residual Regulation, 1997 (Box 17)
    - Privatized Telecommunications: The White Paper and the Public Interest, 1991 (Box 2)
    - Proacted 'Frictional Unemployment' as a Heavy Cost of Technical Progress, 1995 (Box 25)
    - Problems in the construction of Stock Valuation Models, 1968 (Box 4)
    - Production and the Demand for Transportation Services, 1967 (Box 50)
    - Production and the Logic of the Average Variable Cost Test, 1996 (Box 50)
    - Productivity, 1987 (Box 4)
    - Productivity and Related Variables, Undated (Box 4)
    - Productivity and Related Variables: What the Long Run Data Show, 1985; 2 folders (Box 50)
    - Productivity and the Shift to the Services, 1982 (Box 5)
    - Productivity Differences, World-Market Shares and Conflicting National Interest in Linear Trade Models, 1995 (Box 50)
    - Productivity Differences, World-Market Shares and Conflicting National Interest in Linear Trade Models, 1995-1997 (Box 51)
      Reprint and working Paper
    - Productivity Growth Article in Eastern Economic Journal, 1987 (Box 51)
    - Productivity Growth Article in New York Times, 1987 (Box 51)
    - Productivity Growth, Convergence and Welfare: What the Long Run Data Show, 1985-1986; 3 folders (Box 6)
    - Productivity Growth, Convergence, and Welfare: What the Long-Run Data Show, 1986 (Box 51)
    - Productivity Growth, Convergence and Welfare: What the Long Run Data Show, 1983-1986; 19 text files; less than 1 MB. (Digital-materials RL00092-SET-0001, Disk RL00092-FL5-0109)
    - Productivity Growth, International Competitiveness and the Welfare of Nations, 1996 (Box 51)
    - Productivity in Higher Education and the "Cost Disease", 1983 (Box 4)
    - Productivity in Higher Education and the "Cost Disease", 1983 (Box 51)
    - Productivity Incentive Clauses and Rate Adjustment for Inflation, 1982 (Box 5)
    - Productivity Incentive Clauses and Rate Adjustment for Inflation, 1982 (Box 51)
    - Productivity Policy and the Service Sector, 1984-1985; 2 folders (Box 5)
    - Productivity Policy and the Service Sector, 1984 (Box 29)
    - Productivity, rising public service costs and the general welfare, 1993 (Box 6)
    - Productivity, Rising R&D Costs and Unbalanced Growth, 1980; 2 folders (Box 51)
    - Productivity: Reality and Folklore, 1989 (Box 5)
    - Professor Copeland's Study of Money Flows, 1952-1953 (Box 51)
    - Profitability and Energy Output Processes with Negative Net Yields, 1980 (Box 51)
    - Progress in Medical Knowledge and Opportunities for Cost Reduction, undated (Box 51)
    - Progressive, Stagnant, and Asymptotically Stagnant Activities: Some Evidence, 1983-1984; 4 folders (Box 4)
    - Promoting Musical Vitality in New Jersey, 1986 (Box 14)
    - Proposals for a Program to Facilitate the Transfer of Technology to the US, 1992 (Box 34)
    - Protracted Frictional Unemployment as a heavy cost of technical progress, 1996 (Box 36)
    - Public Expenditure Decisions, 1968 (Box 51)
    - Public Interest Rules for Privatized Telecommunications, 1991 (Box 2)
    - Public Support for the Arts: Why and Wherefore, 1997 (Box 18)
    - Public Support for the Arts: Why and Wherefore, 1996 (Box 34)
    - Public-Good Attributes as Independent Justification for Subsidy, 1977 (Box 51)
    - Quality Changes and Productivity Measurement, 1989 (Box 51)
    - Quality Changes and Productivity Measurement: Hedonics and an Alternative, 1989; 2 folders (Box 4)
    - Quasi-Optimal Pricing with Regulated Profit and Interdependent demands, Undated (Box 17)
    - Quasi-optimality: The price we must pay for a price system, 1978 (Box 51)
      Reprint, draft, and correspondence
    - Quasi-Permanence of Price Reductions, 1979 (Box 51)
    - Rail Deregulation, 1979 (Box 26)
    - Rail Deregulation as Possible Model for Telecommunications, 1986 (Box 4)
    - Rapid Economic Growth, Equitable Income Distribution and the Optimal Range of Innovation Spillovers, 2000 (Box 26)
    - Rapid Economic Growth, Equitable Income Distribution, and the Optimal Range of Innovation Spillovers, 2000 (Box 51)
    - Rapidity of Technology Dissemination and Private Enterprise, 1990 (Box 1)
    - Rate Setting Principles under Partial Deregulation, Undated (Box 23)
    - Reality of Economic Illusion; or, In Defense of Excise Taxes, undated (Box 51)
    - Really Thinking Long Run: Keynes' other masterpiece, 2007 (Box 25)
    - Really Thinking Long Run: Keynes's other Masterpiece, 2008 (Box 51)
    - Reasonable and nondiscriminatory (RAND) royalties, standards selection, and control of market power, 2005 (Box 38)
    - Reasonableness and Nondiscriminatory (RAND) Royalties, Standards Selection, and Control of Market Power, 2005 (Box 51)
    - Rebirth of a Fallen Leader: Italy and the Long Period Data, 1985 (Box 51)
      Reprint, working paper, and notes
    - Rebirth of Fallen Leader: Italy and the Long Period Data, 1985 (Box 5)
    - Recent Developments in Mathematical Economics, 1953 (Box 51)
    - Recent Developments in the economics of performing arts, Undated (Box 18)
    - Red-Queen games: arms races, rule of law and market economies, 2004 (Box 51)
    - Red-Queen Games: Arms Races, Rules of Law and Market Economies, 2003 (Box 37)
      Proofs, notes, and related correspondence
    - Redundant Regulation of Foreign Security Trading and US Competitiveness, 1992 (Box 5)
    - Redundant Regulation of Foreign Security Trading and US Competitiveness, Undated (Box 6)
    - Reflections on modern economics, 1989 (Box 3)
    - Regression Results; Test of Convergence Hypothesis for 72 countries, Undated (Box 4)
    - Regulating Emissions of Greenhouse Gases Under Section 202(a) of Clean Air Act, 2006 (Box 24)
    - Regulation Misled by Misread Theory, 2005; 2 folders (Box 51)
      Reprint, presentation, drafts, and correspondence